in this video we're going to talk about
the financial reporting tools that are
available in GP and compare that to the
tools available in business
Central in my GP system here are a few
of the AFA reports that were built to
support financial reporting such as your
balance sheet and income statements in
addition to AFA many GP customers use
management reporter for these reports
because of its Rich feature set
now let's go to business Central and
look at how you can create Financial
reports using account
schedules to navigate to account
schedules select the search icon enter
account schedules and choose it from the
search
results business Central comes with
eight different account schedules out of
the box the first four are used for
charts on the business Central dashboard
the remaining four are financial
statements that are created using a
account subcategories from general
ledger
accounts let's take a look at account
categories in a bit more
detail if you use the cloud migration
tool to migrate your data from GP to
business Central then your accounts and
the categories assigned will get moved
to business
Central if I select the cash account
subcategory on the right side I can see
all the accounts that are included in
this category
in addition I can also see any accounts
in my chart of accounts that are not
currently assigned a category and
therefore will not be included on
account
schedules let's create a new category
and assign the two missing accounts to
that category
now that I've created the new category
and assigned to the accounts business
Central is reminding me to update the
account schedule so these accounts will
now be included on the
reports if we navigate back to the
account schedules let's look at one of
the reports more
closely this message is just reminding
me that the account schedules will be
updated like we just did from the
account categories and if I want to make
a copy we will select no and not make a
copy by selecting the income statement
we can see the details of the makeup of
the report including row definitions as
well as the look and feel of the
report each row is numbered so that you
can create formulas allowing you to sum
up mult multiple accounts or multiple
divide
values you can can also indicate if you
want certain roles bolded or italics or
to start on a new
page if we navigate to the overview then
we can also select the different column
layouts we want for the report as well
as select different date
ranges as you select different date
ranges you can see the amounts change
you can also filter account schedules by
dimensions in this example let's say we
want to filter on our sales department
now I can see expenses for just my sales
department in addition I can also drill
down into each one of the amounts to see
further details on each
line each accounts schedule can also be
exported to
excel in addition if you create account
schedules and want to use it in other
companies you can simply export it and
then import it into other
companies and that's a quick look at
accounts schedules and business Central
that can be used for your financial
reporting
needs to learn more about business
Central see the following resources